[Music] ruby a dynamic interpreted scripting
[音乐]ruby 一种动态解释脚本语言
language made famous for taking simplicity and code readability to the
，以将简单性和代码可读性发挥到极致
extreme it was first conceived by yukihiro matsumoto aka mats in 1993 as
而闻名，它最初由 yukihro matsumoto aka mats 在 1993 年构想为一种
an easy-to-use scripting language like python but with genuine object-oriented
易于使用的脚本语言，如 pytho，但具有真正的面向对象功能
features like smalltalk it exploded in popularity after david hanemeyer hansen
，如 small在 david hanemeyer hansen
aka dhh created rails in 2005 a model view controller framework at the time it
aka dhh 在 2005 年创建了一个模型视图控制器框架 Rails 之后迅速流行起来，当时它
was a game changer for startups because it reduced the complexity required to
是初创公司的游戏规则改变者，因为它降低了
build a full stack web application and has been used to build unicorns like
构建全栈 Web 应用程序所需的复杂性，并已被用于构建独角兽 像
twitter shopify github and airbnb just to name a few ruby is often called a
twitter shopify github 和 airbnb仅举几例 ruby 通常被称为程序
programmer's best friend thanks to its minimal syntax that relies on plain
员最好的朋友，这要归功于它的最小语法，依赖于简单的英语
english words and the use of blocks to write concise functional code at the
单词和使用块来编写简洁的功能代码，同时
same time it's a true object-oriented language where everything is an object
它是一个真正的面向对象一切都是对象
and every object can be modified giving developers the flexibility to extend or
并且每个对象都可以修改的语言，使开发人员可以灵活地扩展或
modify the behavior of the underlying language the developer ecosystem is
修改 底层语言的行为 开发者生态系统
large and mature code is shared between developers with the rubygems package
庞大且成熟的代码在开发者之间通过 rubygems 包管理
manager where a program is organized into a self-contained format called a
器共享，其中程序被组织成一种称为 gem 的自包含格式开始
gem to get started install ruby then create a file ending in rb to declare a
安装 ruby 然后创建一个以 rb 结尾的文件来声明 一
local variable give it a name followed by a value there's no variable keyword
局部变量给它一个名称后跟一个值没有变量关键字，
but you can define constants in all caps or global variables with a dollar sign
但是您可以在所有大写字母或带美元符号的全局变量中定义常量
every value is an instance of an object which means we can call methods directly
每个值都是一个对象的实例，这意味着我们可以
on a string like so and parentheses are usually optional ruby is dynamically
像这样直接在字符串上调用方法 和括号通常是可选的 ruby 是动态类型
typed which means there's no type annotations however modern tools like
的，这意味着没有类型注释，但是像 rbs 这样的现代工具可以
rbs can add a type system on top of it kind of like how typescript does for
在它上面添加一个类型系统，就像 typescript 现在为 javascript 所做的那样，使用
javascript now to print a value to the standard output use the puts method we
puts 方法将值打印到标准输出 我们
can define our own custom methods using the def keyword which end with the end
可以使用以 end 关键字结尾的 def 关键字定义自己的自定义方法，
keyword every method will always return exactly one object no return keyword is
每个方法将始终只返回一个对象 否 return 关键字是
necessary or if you don't want a named method you might create a block with a
必需的，或者如果您不想要命名方法，您可以使用 do 关键字创建一个块，
do keyword which works like an anonymous function blocks can also take arguments
其工作方式类似于匿名函数块也可以采用
found in between the pipe characters now use the class keyword to create
在管道字符之间找到的参数现在使用 class 关键字
blueprints for your own custom objects an interesting point is that ruby
为您创建蓝图 自己的自定义对象一个有趣的点是 ruby
supports duct typing which means that if it walks like a duck and quacks like a
管道类型，这意味着如果它像鸭子一样走路并像鸭子一样嘎嘎叫，那么
duck then it's a duck in other words it won't throw type errors based on the
它就是鸭子，换句话说，它不会基于类本身抛出类型错误，而是
class itself but rather the methods that are implemented on it define the
基于方法在其上实现定义
initialize method to run code when a new object is constructed any variable that
初始化方法以在构造新对象时运行代码任何
starts with at belongs to an object instance while any variable with a
以 at 开头的变量都属于对象实例，而任何带有
double at is static and belongs to the class itself you can easily add getters
double at 的变量都是静态的并且属于类本身，您可以轻松添加 getter
and setters to a class using the attribute accessor method and now we can
和 setter 使用属性访问器方法到一个类，现在我们可以
create a new object instance by calling the new method on the class now run your
通过调用类上的新方法来创建一个新的对象实例现在
code with the ruby interpreter from the terminal this has been ruby in 100
使用 ruby 解释器来运行你的代码 在终端上，这已经在 100
seconds hit the like button and subscribe if you want to see more short
秒内变成了 ruby，如果您想观看更多这样的短视频，请点击“赞”按钮并订阅，谢谢
videos like this thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
观看，我们下期再见